{"questions":[{"difficulty":"1","question":"What is the benefit of using standards (such as IEEE standards) for software development?","answers":["An advantage over competitors because the use of the standard indicates quality, this is true for the organization that sells its products and services as well as for the organization that works on subcontractors.","Defining systematic action processes that were formulated based on the experience of experts. Allows you to rely on that and not reinvent the wheel.","The same terminology, a common language between the people of the organization and the teams working between them, and between organizations.","All of the above."],"correct_ans":"4"},{"difficulty":"1","question":"In black box testing, testers:","answers":["Have knowledge of the internal code structure.","Focus on internal algorithms and data structures.","Test the functionality of the software without knowing its internal workings.","Perform code walkthroughs to identify defects."],"correct_ans":"3"},{"difficulty":"1","question":"White box testing focuses on:","answers":["Testing the functionality of the software without knowing its internal workings.","Testing the internal code structure and logic of the software.","Identifying defects based on user requirements.","Testing the software in real-world scenarios."],"correct_ans":"2"},{"difficulty":"2","question":"Which of the following is an example of a functional requirement for a social media application? ","answers":["The system must support 1000 concurrent users.","Users must be able to post messages to their timeline.","The system must have a response time of less than 500 milliseconds.","The system must be compatible with iOS and Android devices."],"correct_ans":"2"},{"difficulty":"3","question":"Non-functional requirements are concerned with:","answers":["Describing the system's behavior and interactions.","Defining the internal structure and design of the system.","Specifying the performance, usability, and reliability characteristics of the system.","Identifying the hardware and software components needed to implement the system."],"correct_ans":"3"},{"difficulty":"3","question":"Which of the following is a problem with using natural language for requirement specification?","answers":["Lack of clarity \u2013 precision is difficult without making the document difficult to read.","Not universal \u2013 users and customers may not understand the document.","Compliance with Standards \u2013 many industry standards and regulatory bodies recommend or require not using natural language for documenting requirements.","None of the above is a problem with using natural language."],"correct_ans":"1"},{"difficulty":"3","question":"Scenarios are real-life examples of how a system can be used. Which of the following should NOT be included in scenarios?","answers":["A description of the starting situation.","A description of what can go wrong.","Information about other concurrent activities.","Assumptions or speculation about how the user might interact with the system."],"correct_ans":"4"},{"difficulty":"2","question":"Which phase is the longest and most expensive in the software life cycle?","answers":["Requirements phase","Implementation phase","Maintenance phase","Specification phase"],"correct_ans":"3"},{"difficulty":"2","question":"Agile processes are:","answers":["Processes where all of the process activities are planned in advance and progress is measured against this plan.","Processes where planning is incremental, and it is easier to change the process to reflect changing customer requirements.","Processes which are limited to a very short period of time and therefore eliminate any testing to save time.","Processes where the customer is only involved in the beginning at the requirements phase to explain what they want in the system."],"correct_ans":"2"},{"difficulty":"3","question":"What is true about Incremental delivery?","answers":["Early increments act as a prototype to help elicit requirements for later increments.","Results in lower risk of overall project failure.","The highest priority system services tend to receive the most testing.","All of the above."],"correct_ans":"4"},{"difficulty":"3","question":"The essential attributes of good software are:","answers":["Maintainability, Efficiency, Acceptability, Dependability and security.","Reusability, Efficiency, Adaptability and security.","Accuracy and security.","Affordability, Dependability, Maintainability, Efficiency and security."],"correct_ans":"1"},{"difficulty":"3","question":"What are the approximate costs of software engineering?","answers":["Roughly 40% of software costs are development costs, 60% are testing costs.","80% of software costs are testing costs while 20% are development costs.","Roughly 60% of software costs are development costs, 40% are testing costs.","Costs vary highly depending on the project."],"correct_ans":"3"},{"difficulty":"2","question":"Which of the following is a phase in the software life cycle?","answers":["Testing phase.","Design phase.","Documentation phase.","Verification phase."],"correct_ans":"2"},{"difficulty":"1","question":"A software can be tested as a:","answers":["Black box (functional) and White box (structural).","Black box only, because we don't have knowledge about the implemented software when we are testing.","White box only, because the software structure is known therefore, we can't look at the software as a black box.","None of the above."],"correct_ans":"1"},{"difficulty":"2","question":"What is the testing phase in the software life cycle?","answers":["A phase that comes after the development phase to ensure the code is working as expected.","A phase that can be executed at any stage depending on the choice of the developer.","There is no such phase as testing is done all throughout the software life cycle.","A phase after the software is handed to the customer, in which the customer checks if the software implements the functional and non-functional requirements."],"correct_ans":"3"},{"difficulty":"2","question":"A scrum master is:","answers":["The person who represents the customer's interest.","A facilitator for both the Product Owner and the Team.","Someone who has management authority and commits to work on behalf of the Team.","Someone who defines goals for the overall project."],"correct_ans":"2"},{"difficulty":"2","question":"A product owner is:","answers":["The person who represents the customer's interest.","Someone who defines goals for the overall project.","Someone who is aware of the requirements\/featured and their sequence.","All of the above."],"correct_ans":"4"},{"difficulty":"3","question":"Which meetings are conducted in the scrum agile development methodology?","answers":["Sprint planning meeting, daily scrum meetings, sprint review meeting, sprint retrospective meeting, and backlog refinement meeting.","Sprint planning meeting, daily scrum meetings, sprint review meeting.","Weekly scrum meetings, sprint planning meeting, project summary meeting.","Meetings are scheduled based on the team's needs and will be specified in the scrum report."],"correct_ans":"1"},{"difficulty":"1","question":"What is the correct order in git when we want to make changes to the code?","answers":["git push --> git commit --> git pull","git push --> git pull --> git commit","git pull --> git commit --> git push","git pull --> git push --> git commit"],"correct_ans":"3"},{"difficulty":"2","question":"Which of the following is NOT an architecture pattern?","answers":["Model, View, Controller","UML","Layered","Client-Server"],"correct_ans":"2"},{"difficulty":"1","question":"What is true about performing unit tests by an independent tester:","answers":["It is important because the tester is objective, but on the other hand it requires learning time to get familiar with the code.","It is an excellent choice because it allows the team to utilize their time in other parts of the project instead of testing, but it is not a cost-effective choice, as it requires paying an extra person outside of the team.","It is efficient because the tester will only perform tests on certain parts of the code that are clear and easy for the tester to understand.","This is the only way to perform unit tests."],"correct_ans":"1"},{"difficulty":"3","question":"Which of the following is an automated test component?","answers":["A setup part, where you initialize the system with the test case, namely the inputs and expected outputs.","A call part, where you call the object or method to be tested.","An assertion part where you compare the result of the call with the expected result. If the assertion evaluates to true, the test has been successful, if false, then it has failed.","All of the above."],"correct_ans":"4"},{"difficulty":"3","question":"Select the wrong statement:","answers":["Testing can only show the presence of errors in a program. It cannot demonstrate that there are no remaining faults.","The documentation phase in the software life cycle is essential and comes after the implementation phase.","Commonly used Architectural patterns include model-view-controller, layered architecture, repository, client\u2013server, and pipe and filter.","Wherever possible, you should write automated tests. The tests are embedded in a program that can be run every time a change is made to a system."],"correct_ans":"2"},{"difficulty":"3","question":"Which of the following is true?","answers":["In white box testing we have no knowledge about the implemented software.","Drivers are considered as the dummy modules that always simulate the low-level modules.","Test Case is a document which describes how we are going to come up with testing for a particular application.","Reviews are a scheduling assessment."],"correct_ans":"3"},{"difficulty":"2","question":"Which is true regarding Reviews?","answers":["They are meetings conducted by technical people for technical people.","They are a technical assessment of a work product created during the software engineering process.","They are a software quality assurance mechanism.","All the of the above is true regarding reviews."],"correct_ans":"4"},{"difficulty":"2","question":"Which of the following statements is true?","answers":["Requirements validation is the process of checking the requirements for validity, consistency, completeness, realism and verifiability. ","Reviews are a project budget summary.","Stubs are considered as the dummy modules that always simulate the high-level modules.","All of the above."],"correct_ans":"1"},{"difficulty":"1","question":"What is the difference between a sprint backlog and a product backlog?","answers":["A sprint backlog is a subset of Product Backlog Items, which define the work for a Sprint.","Any stakeholder (including the Team) can add items to the product backlog while a sprint backlog is created only by Team members.","A sprint backlog usually has more details than the product backlog including: planned hours and primary person responsible to do the work during the Sprint.","All of the above differences are true."],"correct_ans":"4"},{"difficulty":"2","question":"Factors affecting software pricing are:","answers":["Market opportunity, Contractual terms and Requirements volatility.","Cost estimate uncertainty and Financial health.","Market opportunity and Development team members.","Answers 1+2."],"correct_ans":"4"},{"difficulty":"1","question":"In black box testing graph, the nodes represent:","answers":["Properties","Entities","Relations","Answers 1+3"],"correct_ans":"2"},{"difficulty":"2","question":"Which is true regarding Reviews?","answers":["They are meetings conducted by technical people for technical people.","They are a technical assessment of a work product created during the software engineering process.","They are a software quality assurance mechanism.","All the of the above is true regarding reviews."],"correct_ans":"4"},{"difficulty":"1","question":"What are some architectural design decisions that architects need to make?","answers":[" Choice of Programming Language.","System Documentation Techniques.","Distribution Strategy.","All of the Above."],"correct_ans":"3"},{"difficulty":"1","question":"What is the primary purpose of a user story in agile development?","answers":["Define technical specifications.","Document code structure.","Describe a feature from the user's perspective."," Create project timelines."],"correct_ans":"3"},{"difficulty":"1","question":"What is the primary objective of adaptive maintenance in software development?","answers":["Addressing and fixing errors in the software.","Enhancing the software to improve performance.","Adapting the software to changes in the external environment.","Implementing new features to meet user requirements."],"correct_ans":"3"},{"difficulty":"1","question":"What is MVC?","answers":["Main-View-Connector, it is the main connector between the code and the graphics.","Main-Version-Commit, it is a type of commit in GitHub.","Main-View-Controller, it is an architecture pattern.","Maximum-Vendor-Control, it is a contract signed with hardware vendors."],"correct_ans":"3"},{"difficulty":"2","question":"ggggggg","answers":["gggg f","ggggg","gggggggggg","gggggggggggg"],"correct_ans":"1"}]}